ART FRICK

(646) 400-8927 • artfrick@gmail.com

PROFILE

Creative and results-driven individual with a background in technology and web design, with excellent communication and presentation skills, considerable experience in dealing with diverse groups of people, teaching experience, public speaking experience, and a solid work ethic.

CORE SKILLS

Proactive • Goal-oriented • Positive attitude • Natural leader • Team player

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2012-Present | University of New Hampshire - Institute on Disability | Westchester, NY & Durham, NH

Mission: The Institute on Disability at the University of New Hampshire focuses on the improvement of knowledge, policies, and practices related to the lives of persons with disabilities and their families.

Web Designer - Information Technologist II

- Design and develop accessible solutions for all web-based needs of the organization
- Upgrade and revamp websites for increased usability and performance
- Formulate plans for web-based dissemination of information per grant requirements
- Provide user and systems-level technical support and development for the organization
- Manage external vendor/project relations

2008-2012 | Freelance Designer/Developer | New York, NY

Mission: Provided marketing, web and graphic design, and development services to a diverse client base.

Designer/Developer

- Created user interfaces and web assets, including banners ads, Flash animations, and photography
- Developed timelines and maintained client expectations
- Managed freelance and full-time staff members

2006-2008 | Starlite Media, LLC | New York, NY

Mission: Starlite Media is a full service, place-based outdoor advertising company

Vice President of Marketing and Creative Services

- Oversaw all marketing endeavors, including industry event planning, online marketing, and publicity
- Attended industry events to promote products and gain exposure among senior-level media buyers
- Conceptualized, designed, and coordinated production of all sales materials
- Managed department staff and developed internship program

GRANTS

2016-2017 | ALT TEXT TOOLS | Wikimedia Foundation Individual Engagement Grant

- Suite of tools to be developed for improving text alternatives across the Wikipedia ecosystem
- Award amount: \$14,000

PRESENTATIONS & WEBINARS

2016

- A Beginners Guide to Creating Accessible Documents Webinar
- NYC Drupalcamp WCAG 2.0 and You
- Drupaldelphia Accessibility Information and Solutions for Everyone
- NJ Drupalcamp Web Accessibility 101
- Web Accessibility Standards and the Institute on Disability Webinar

2015

• NYC Drupalcamp - Introduction to Accessible Web Development

2014

AUCD Annual Meeting - Effective Communication Strategies

EDUCATION

2014-2017(est) | University of New Hampshire | Durham, NH

- M.B.A. Candidate
- 4.0 GPA

2002-2006 | Parsons School of Design | New York, NY

- B.F.A., Fine Arts
- Graduated with a 3.61 GPA

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Adobe CC Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- HTML/CSS/JS/PHP/ASP.NET
- WordPress, Drupal, Sitefinity, and Kentico CMS experience
- Version Control (GIT)
- Relational databases (MySQL, MS Access)
- ARIA-spec and WCAG 2.0 standard compliance auditing
- Microsoft Office
- Windows and Redhat Server administration, setup, and deployment
- Microsoft Active Directory
- Remote systems support
- Classroom and professional-setting teaching experience
- Able to interact and work with large groups of people
- Managerial experience
- Excellent presentation skills
- Able to translate ideas into reality